TAYLOUR KROEKER

J 604-700-6116 | ★ taylour.em@gmail.com | ♠ tailorem | ♥ Vancouver, BC



SUMMARY

Junior full-stack web developer excited by collaborative problem solving, creating beautiful, responsive interfaces and building efficient, sustainable systems. Continually seeking to strengthen my abilities as a developer, I revel in learning new concepts and applying best practices in my code. My 5 year history in the retail industry has encouraged my sense of dedication, persistence and enthusiasm, as well as strong interpersonal and organizational skills. When not at my keyboard, I can generally be found painting, downhill skateboarding or discovering a new passion.

PROJECTS

CrabbyApp - A real-time, multi-user chat application built with React, WebSockets and Express. https://github.com/tailorem/chattyApp

Bendito - A responsive, team-built food-ordering and order management application that communicates with clients via SMS. Coded majority of admin page (front and back end functionality), initialized database, assisted with responsiveness of menu navbar and implementing overall visual layout. Built with JavaScript, PostgreSQL, Express, Twilio API, Ajax, jQuery and HTML/CSS/SASS with Bootstrap. http://bendito.herokuapp.com/

Relephant - A single-page Twitter-clone that allows users to anonymously share posts (and shortened URLs). Created using JavaScript, Express, Node.js, MongoDB, jQuery, Ajax and HTML/CSS and hosted on Heroku. http://relephant.herokuapp.com/

TinyApp - A multi-page app enabling users to create and share shortened URLs. Coded following RESTful practices, using Node.js Express, HTML, EJS templating and custom CSS. https://github.com/tailorem/tinyapp

EDUCATION

Lighthouse Labs, Vancouver — Web Development

JUL 2018-SEP 2018

- Intensive full-stack web development bootcamp
- 500+ hours of mentor-assisted project-based programming
- Building apps using HTML/CSS, JavaScript, SQL, React and more

EXPERIENCE

Omer DeSerres, Vancouver

Assistant Manager MAR 2017-JUL 2018 (& ARP 2016-AUG 2016)

- Managed daily store operations and staff scheduling
- Supported, trained and worked alongside staff in all departments
- Communicated daily with head office, suppliers and other locations

Merchandiser JUL 2014-MAR 2017

- Designed effective product layouts based on customer behavior
- Created compelling displays through analysis of inventory and sales data
- Led full restructuring of store layout and assisted setup of new location

Sales Associate OCT 2012-JUL 2014

- Encouraged customers to return by creating a welcoming atmosphere
- Utilized arts knowledge to assist customers in making informed decisions
- Operated POS system, maintained store stock and cleanliness

Environmental Youth Alliance, Vancouver

Youth Mentor JUL 2012-JUL 2013

- Guided youth at community-oriented events such as market plant giveaways
- Prepared weekly informational materials and led activities to teach gardening skills
- Aided in maintenance of community garden space

SKILLS

Languages JavaScript HTML5 CSS/SASS Rubu

Libraries & Frameworks

Node.is Express. is i0ueru AJAX React & JSX

Databases

MongoDB PostgreSQL Knex.js

VCS & Testing Git Mocha/Chai

Additional Photoshop Lightroom